[
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 1,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "A short and witty poem is known as",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "a ballad",
            "an epigram",
            "an epic",
            "a lyric"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 2,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "A literary work which extols one's virtues and accomplishments is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "a eulogy",
            "a pastoral",
            "an elegy",
            "an allegory"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 3,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "George Orwell's Animal Farm is an example of a",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "farce",
            "burlesque",
            "satire",
            "lampoon"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 4,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "A poem of lamentation on death is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "a lyric",
            "a ballad",
            "an ode",
            "an elegy"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 5,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "The misuse of words that sound somewhat similar is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "malapropism",
            "metonymy",
            "onomatopoeia",
            "pun"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 6,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "The main character in a literary work is the",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "anatagonist",
            "protagonist",
            "narrator",
            "villan"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 7,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "A speech delivered by a character who is alone on the stage is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "a soliloquy",
            "a chorus",
            "a dialogue",
            "an aside"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 8,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "A sonnet may be divided into an octave and a",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "tercet",
            "quatrain",
            "sestet",
            "couplet"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 9,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "''All hands on deck'' is an example of",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "personification",
            "metonymy",
            "metaphor",
            "synecdoche"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 10,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "In poetry.....consist of four lines",
        "explanation": "''Soft as he mourned, the streams forgot to flow<br>She flocks around a dumb compassion show''",
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "a sestet",
            "a quatrain",
            "an octave",
            "a tercet"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 11,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "The dominant device used in the lines above is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "oxymoron",
            "mock-heroic",
            "pathetic fallacy",
            "satire"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 12,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "In the above lines, ''flow,'' and ''show''",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "alliterate",
            "contrast",
            "rhyme",
            "parallel"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 13,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "The above lines constitute a",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "couplet",
            "rhythm",
            "tercet",
            "rhyme"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 14,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "''I have read Shakespeare' is an example of",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "litotes",
            "paradox",
            "parody",
            "metonymy"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 15,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Twelfth Night is an example of",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "farce",
            "comedy",
            "tragi-comedy",
            "burlesque"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 16,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "In ''The fair breeze below, the white foam flew, The furrow followed free, the dominant device used is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "metaphor",
            "personification",
            "alliteration",
            "assonance"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 17,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "An address to an object or person not present is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "apostrophe",
            "synecdoche",
            "paradox",
            "epigram"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 18,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "The expression '' poisonous pleasure of wine'' Illustrates the use of",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "metonymy",
            "synecdoche",
            "paradox",
            "oxymoron"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 19,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "A non-verbal story-telling by a character on stage is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "imitation",
            "farce",
            "mime",
            "comedy"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 20,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "A character that develops with events and situations in a novel is a ......character",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "flat",
            "sound",
            "minor",
            "main"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 21,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>Read the poem below and answer the question<br><br>Now, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>And Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>Though Pleasure's free, she cannot sing<br>As sweet a song as Joy confined.<br><br>Pleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>And dances by false glare at night;<br>But joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>To spread its wings in Nature's light.<br><br>The poem says that ''Joy'' is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "for the poor",
            "natural and satisfying",
            "artificial and transitory",
            "for lovers"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 22,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>Read the poem below and answer the question<br><br>Now, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>And Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>Though Pleasure's free, she cannot sing<br>As sweet a song as Joy confined.<br><br>Pleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>And dances by false glare at night;<br>But joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>To spread its wings in Nature's light.<br><br>The dominant device used in presenting ''Joy'' and ''Pleasure'' in the first stanza is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "diction",
            "oxymoron",
            "personification",
            "conceit"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 23,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>Read the poem below and answer the question<br><br>Now, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>And Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>Though Pleasure's free, she cannot sing<br>As sweet a song as Joy confined.<br><br>Pleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>And dances by false glare at night;<br>But joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>To spread its wings in Nature's light.<br><br>The feelings associated with ''Jy'' and ''Pleasure'' in the first stanza is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "rhyme",
            "euphemism",
            "assonance",
            "contrast"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 24,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>Read the poem below and answer the question<br><br>Now, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>And Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>Though Pleasure's free, she cannot sing<br>As sweet a song as Joy confined.<br><br>Pleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>And dances by false glare at night;<br>But joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>To spread its wings in Nature's light.<br><br>''False glare'' refers to",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "man-made light",
            "nature's light",
            "the moon's light",
            "the sun's light"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 25,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "UNSEEN PROSE AND POETRY<br>Read the poem below and answer the question<br><br>Now, Joy is born of parents poor,<br>And Pleasure of our richer kind;<br>Though Pleasure's free, she cannot sing<br>As sweet a song as Joy confined.<br><br>Pleasure's a moth, that sleeps by day<br>And dances by false glare at night;<br>But joy's a Butterfly, that loves<br>To spread its wings in Nature's light.<br><br>''Pleasure's moth'' is an example of a (n)",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "irony",
            "hyperbole",
            "metaphor",
            "simile"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 26,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the passage below and answer the question:<br><br>The long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br><br>A suitable title for the passage is the",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "March of Soldiers",
            "Agony of War",
            "Pangs of Hunger",
            "Dread of Desease"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 27,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the passage below and answer the question:<br><br>The long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br><br>The writer's mood is one of",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "anger",
            "fear",
            "pity",
            "disappointment"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 28,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the passage below and answer the question:<br><br>The long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br><br>The mood is expressed through the use of",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "objects",
            "scenery",
            "syntax",
            "diction"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 29,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the passage below and answer the question:<br><br>The long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br><br>The attitude of the survivors is best summed up by the word",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "indifference",
            "persistence",
            "resignation",
            "victory"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 30,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the passage below and answer the question:<br><br>The long column of misery tended continually to grow longer, as the more robust struggled to get as far as possible from the pursuing French, and as the weaker fell farther and farther behind. There were enough weaklings in all conscience; even in summer the had been badly clothed, and even in victory insufficiently fed, and now it was winter, and Espinosa had been fought and lost, and the route of the retreat lay away from the fertile plains and up into the inhospitable mountains. The rain had fallen upon them in deluges for days and now as they climbed higher it was turning into sleet. and a bitter cold wind blew. Ahead of them they could see the snow lying thick on the mountain passes through which they would have to climb, without food or fuel or rest, and with the terror of the French to urge them on. Disease had come inevitably to complete the work so well begun by hunger, exposure, and the sword<br><br>The device used in the last sentence is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "climax",
            "sarcasm",
            "euphemism",
            "hyperbole"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 31,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>So please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>But from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>The element itself, till seven years heat,<br>Shall not behold her face at ample view......<br>(Act 1 Scene 1)<br><br>The speaker is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "Cesario",
            "Fabian",
            "Valentine",
            "Feste"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 32,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>So please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>But from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>The element itself, till seven years heat,<br>Shall not behold her face at ample view......<br>(Act 1 Scene 1)<br><br>''Element'' in the third line refers to the",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "sky",
            "weather",
            "sun",
            "cloud"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 33,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>So please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>But from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>The element itself, till seven years heat,<br>Shall not behold her face at ample view......<br>(Act 1 Scene 1)<br><br>The report is made to",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "Olivia",
            "Malvolio",
            "Viola",
            "Orsino"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 34,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>So please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>But from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>The element itself, till seven years heat,<br>Shall not behold her face at ample view......<br>(Act 1 Scene 1)<br><br>The one referred to by the speaker is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "Maria",
            "Olivia",
            "Sir Tony",
            "Viola"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 35,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE: Twelfth Night<br>Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>So please my lord, I might not be admitted;<br>But from her handmaid to return this answer:<br>The element itself, till seven years heat,<br>Shall not behold her face at ample view......<br>(Act 1 Scene 1)<br><br>The message is in connection with",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "warfare",
            "love",
            "revenge",
            "shipwreck"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 36,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>B : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the<br>Malignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>therefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>(Act II Scene 1)<br><br>The above dialogue is between",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "Viola and Captain",
            "Captain and Sebastian",
            "Antonio and Sebastian",
            "Sebastian and Olivia"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 37,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>B : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the<br>Malignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>therefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>(Act II Scene 1)<br><br>Speaker B requests Speaker A to",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "be patient",
            "stay behind",
            "go back home",
            "pray for his friend"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 38,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>B : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the<br>Malignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>therefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>(Act II Scene 1)<br><br>Speaker B is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "grateful",
            "happy",
            "angry",
            "sad"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 39,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>B : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the<br>Malignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>therefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>(Act II Scene 1)<br><br>The scene of his action is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "a street",
            "the sea-coast",
            "Orsino's palace",
            "Olivia's palace"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 40,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : Will you stay no longer nor will you not that I go with you?<br>B : By your patience, no. My stars shine darkly over me; the<br>Malignancy of my fate might, perhaps, distemper yours;<br>therefore I shall crave of you your leave that I may bear my evils alone<br>(Act II Scene 1)<br><br>The underlined sentence means that my",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "faith will rescue you",
            "malice will destroy you",
            "ill-luck may affect you",
            "bad temper will hurt you"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 41,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : How dost thou like this tune?<br>B : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>Where Love is throned<br>A : Thou dost speak masterly<br>My life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>Hath stayed upon some favour that it loves;<br>Hath is not, boy?<br>B : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br><br>Speaker A is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "Sir Toby",
            "Sir Andrew",
            "Duke Orsino",
            "Countess Olivia"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 42,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : How dost thou like this tune?<br>B : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>Where Love is throned<br>A : Thou dost speak masterly<br>My life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>Hath stayed upon some favour that it loves;<br>Hath is not, boy?<br>B : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br><br>The two speakers are in",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 2,
        "options": [
            "the garden",
            "a ship",
            "the Duke's palace",
            "Olivia's house"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 43,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : How dost thou like this tune?<br>B : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>Where Love is throned<br>A : Thou dost speak masterly<br>My life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>Hath stayed upon some favour that it loves;<br>Hath is not, boy?<br>B : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br><br>The relationship between speaker A and B is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "master-servant",
            "brother-sister",
            "husband-wife",
            "mistress-steward"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 44,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : How dost thou like this tune?<br>B : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>Where Love is throned<br>A : Thou dost speak masterly<br>My life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>Hath stayed upon some favour that it loves;<br>Hath is not, boy?<br>B : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br><br>The scene reveals",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "Orsino's love for Olivia",
            "Viola's love for Orsino",
            "Olivia's love for Sebastian",
            "Olivia's love for Cesario"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 45,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>A : How dost thou like this tune?<br>B : It gives a very echo to the seat<br>Where Love is throned<br>A : Thou dost speak masterly<br>My life upon't , young though thou art, thine eye<br>Hath stayed upon some favour that it loves;<br>Hath is not, boy?<br>B : A little, by your favour (Act ll Scene 4)<br><br>The dialogue shows that the characters are",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "in love with each other",
            "truly in love with music",
            "in love with the same person",
            "both victims of unreturned love"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 46,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>I am not weary, and 't is long to night.<br>I pray you, let us satisfy our eyes<br>With the memorials and the things of fame<br>That do renown this city<br>(Act III Scene 3)<br><br>The speaker is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 3,
        "options": [
            "Malvolio",
            "Viola",
            "Antonio",
            "Sebastian"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 47,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>I am not weary, and 't is long to night.<br>I pray you, let us satisfy our eyes<br>With the memorials and the things of fame<br>That do renown this city<br>(Act III Scene 3)<br><br>The speaker is addressing",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "Malvolio",
            "Antonio",
            "Valentine",
            "Sebastian"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 48,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br><br>I am not weary, and 't is long to night.<br>I pray you, let us satisfy our eyes<br>With the memorials and the things of fame<br>That do renown this city<br>(Act III Scene 3)<br><br>The person addressed responds to the speaker's request by",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "declining it",
            "accepting it",
            "being undecided",
            "being angry"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 49,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br>......;she<br>Sends him purpose that I may appear stub<br>born to him ; for she incites me to that in the letter.<br>''Cast thy humble slough,''<br>says she; ''be opposite with a kinsman, surly<br>with servant;.......<br><br>The speaker is",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 0,
        "options": [
            "Malvolio",
            "Sebastian",
            "Orsino",
            "Sir Toby"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    },
    {
        "course": "literature",
        "institution": "waec",
        "order": 50,
        "year": 2000,
        "question": "Read the extract below and answer the question<br>......;she<br>Sends him purpose that I may appear stub<br>born to him ; for she incites me to that in the letter.<br>''Cast thy humble slough,''<br>says she; ''be opposite with a kinsman, surly<br>with servant;.......<br><br>The letter referred to is from",
        "explanation": null,
        "correctIndex": 1,
        "options": [
            "Sir Andrew",
            "Maria",
            "Olivia",
            "Cesario"
        ],
        "type": "objectives"
    }
]